Well, so I had a task of deploying this ecommerce
website, but I've decided to make it a bit more interesting and
do it from the Oracle Virtualbox manager with the
help of vagrant and a virtual image of Sentos
nine. As you can see, I've already sshed
from my Ubuntu to the virtual Centos.
I've also configured my Vs code,
it's SH from my Ubuntu to Sentos.
I began with configuring firewall D, which is a dynamic
firewall management tool. It's a high level device that abstracts
away the manual manipulating of iptables.
I've used it to split the traffic into
let me just show you here so you
can see the 3306. It's the default
port number for the SQL database. In our case it's MariaDB.
And I've created another port which
is for the HTP to traffic. The default number is
80. After that I proceeded
with installing MariaDB. Then I created
a database by the name of ecomdb.
I run this script over here,
this SQL script. Then I've installed the
Apache HTTP server. As you can see
it's active running. One important thing when configuring
the Apache HTTP server is let me just show you, it's to
change the default directory index from index HTML
to index PhP as it's in our case it's the
PHP homepage. If you don't change it,
you'll probably be greeted by the default Apache HTML
page which you don't really want. And I
think that's all. So let's see, our server is up and running
and we can check the website on localhost 80.
So it just works. This whole thing
was the so called all in one type of deployment
architecture, which means basically that all components are installed
and run on a single server, which in this case
is my virtual centos. Of course this type of
architecture is not recommended for a bigger project because you can hardly
scale up. And also my server is
the single point of failure. So if something bad happens
to my pc, well I'm losing my job and my house.